windriver.com 2018-10-04

# Privacy - Terms and Conditions

## WIND RIVER PRIVACY NOTICE

Wind River® Systems, Inc. ("Wind River") has created this privacy notice (the “Privacy Notice” or “Notice”) to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The Privacy Notice describes our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website and Wind River’s products and services.

### Information Collection and Use

In order to access certain products or services on our site, users may need to provide their contact information (such as name, company name, mailing address, and email address), which may be used to send orders, deliver the desired products or services, respond to customer service requests, provide alerts such as security updates or changes in our policies, and to send advertising or informational materials like newsletters or white papers, in accordance with your communication preferences.

Similarly, when you subscribe to a newsletter, create an account, make a purchase or request information from Wind River, we may ask for things like contact, billing, shipping and communication information, payment card or financial account data, and account ID or credentials in order to fulfil your request. If you attend a trade show or event or otherwise contact us, you may also voluntarily provide us with similar information. Depending on the service or product that we are providing, we may also collect additional information such as location data and specific technical information about the user's development environment to enhance product functionality and better understand the needs of our customers.

We may also obtain information through partners, vendors, suppliers and other third parties. These enterprises largely fall into the following categories: marketing companies, data set and information vendors, public database providers, social media platforms, partners, providers of products or services, hosts or vendors at events or trade shows, research partners, customers and enterprises that deploy Wind River’s products or services. We take steps to confirm that information we receive from these third parties has been collected with your consent or that these parties are otherwise legally permitted to disclose your personal information to us.

IP addresses are automatically transmitted as part of any internet communication, and we use IP addresses to help diagnose problems with our server, to administer our website and to gather broad demographic information.

Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings or communications at any time by following the instructions set forth in the access/choice/opt-out section below.

### Sharing with Third Parties

Personal information may be shared with or disclosed to third parties in the following ways:

  * To our affiliate entities and subsidiaries for the purposes described in this Privacy Notice.
  * To our partners when you access the documents, products or programs available on the Wind River Marketplace.
  * To our authorized service providers and suppliers who provide services to us such as web site hosting, data analysis, payment processing, human resources and employment related services, information technology and related infrastructure provision, customer service, marketing, email delivery, credit card processing, auditing and other similar services.
  * To our third party advertising company partners to prepare and deliver advertising content, to provide content services and to enable them to provide you with more personalized ads and to study the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns.
  * To a third party in the event of any contemplated or actual reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).
  * As we believe is required, necessary, or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process and/or to respond to requests from competent public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations and those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, security, safety, and physical and intellectual property, and/or the rights of our affiliates, you, or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.
  * To any other person or entity where you consent to the disclosure.

Certain features available through the Wind River website allow you to access websites, documents, programs and products offered by companies other than Wind River. Wind River is not responsible for the policies and practices of such third parties, including policies and practices related to privacy and security, data collection, processing, use, storage and disclosure.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of information that is written to and read from your hard drive by your browser at the request of our Web pages. Information stored in cookies is not accessible to web pages from other websites. Cookies themselves cannot retrieve any information about you or your computer's configuration.

Wind River may save information regarding your visit to our website in the form of a cookie to allow the following:

  * A personalized browsing experience
  * Better tracking of usage of our websites in order to improve the content of our websites
  * Analyze your visiting patterns to improve our websites
  * To save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our support website
  * Deliver advertising, communications, and content from us and third parties, on our websites and those of third parties, specific to your interests
  * If you register on one of our websites, or otherwise provide us with your personal information, we may associate that information with other information we collect from or about you or that you provide, information regarding your use of our websites, or information we receive from or about you from third parties. We will use this combined data for marketing and analytics purposes

We collect only the domain name of visitors to our web pages, aggregate information on what pages users access, and information volunteered by the user, such as information provided for a survey, registration, or contest form.

We do not collect email addresses of unregistered visitors.

You may choose to reject cookies either outright, or on a case-by-case basis by using the settings in your internet browser.

### Feedback

The user can submit feedback via [webmaster@windriver.com](mailto:webmaster@windriver.com). Any feedback that is submitted through this area becomes the property of Wind River. We may use this feedback, such as success stories, for marketing purposes, or to contact you for further feedback on the site.

### Resumes

Wind River will process job applicant personal information for recruitment and hiring purposes. Recruitment purposes includes communicating with you, internally evaluating your qualifications and skills, preparing for interview or screening discussions (including arranging travel where applicable or reimbursing candidates for expense), and may entail background checks for certain roles, which will be conducted with additional notice and in accordance with applicable laws. Resumes submitted to Wind River for review should only include information relevant to job qualifications and employment history including prior employment, relevant positions and dates, significant accomplishments, education, degrees or certifications obtained, dates and issuing institutions and other relevant awards or achievements. During the hiring process we may obtain information about you from publicly available sources or from third parties including references, background check suppliers, and the like. We take steps to confirm that information we receive from these third parties has been collected with your consent or that these parties are otherwise legally permitted to disclose your personal information to us.

You may remove your resume from our searchable database at any time by sending a request using the contact information below.

### Contests

We run contests on our site in which we ask users for contact information (such as their email address). We use contact data from our contests to send users information about our company. The user's contact information is also used to contact the user when necessary. Users may opt-out of receiving future mailings; see the choice/opt-out section below.

### Public Forums

This site makes news groups available to its users at news://comp.os.vxworks/ and groups.google.com/group/comp.os.vxworks/. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information, or any other information, online.

### Security

Wind River uses industry standard efforts to safeguard the confidentiality of your personal identifiable information, such as firewalls and Secure Socket Layers. However, No technology, data transmission or system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that your password to any Wind River account has been compromised), please immediately notify us by contacting us using the information provided below.

We cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personally identifiable information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Privacy Notice. By way of example (without limiting the foregoing), we may be forced to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, or third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications. Further, we can (and you authorize us to) disclose any information about you to law enforcement or other government officials as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate.

### Legal Basis for Our Use (EEA only)

If you are in the European Economic Area, our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it. The following sections provide additional information under the EU General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") and national data protection law. We will collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, where we have a legal obligation to do so or where the processing is in our legitimate interests (such as processing for administrative purposes, direct marketing, product development or improvement, preventing fraud or criminal acts and in support of information security) and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms. 

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, this will be clear at the time of collection. We will also tell you whether the requirement for that information is mandatory and explain any consequences to you if you do not provide the information. 

Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information based on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will take reasonable steps to provide clear notice and describe our legitimate interests.

Wind River Systems, Inc. or one of its subsidiaries is a Data Controller of all personal information collected in the EEA, except where a supplemental privacy notice says otherwise. The contact details for Wind River Systems, Inc. are set out below.

If you believe we are using your personal information in a way that is inconsistent with this Privacy Notice or for more information about your rights, contact your local data protection authority (contact details for data protection authorities in the European Economic Area are available here.)

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information for any specific processing activity, please contact us using the contact details provided under the “Contacting Wind River” Section below.

### International Compliance

Wind River is a global company with its headquarters in the United States. As such, we may transfer your personal information between the United States and our affiliates and subsidiaries in other countries. We may also transfer your personal information to our third party service providers, who may be located in a different country to you.

We transfer information in order to operate efficiently, to improve performance, and to create redundancies in order to protect information in the event of an outage or other problem. We will process your personal information in a way that meets the commitments of this Notice and complies with the law wherever we transfer it. Whenever Wind River transfers personal information beyond the country of origin, we will do so in accordance with applicable laws.

### Retention

We retain personal information for the period necessary to: provide requested products or services, as needed to comply with legal obligations (e.g. maintaining opt-out lists to fulfill advertising choices or to comply mandatory record retention or legal hold requirements), as agreed in an individual consent, to resolve disputes, and to otherwise fulfill the purposes, rights and obligations outlined in this Privacy Notice. Retention periods can vary significantly based on the type of information and how it is used and our retention periods are based on criteria that include legally mandated retention periods, pending or potential litigation, our intellectual property or ownership rights, contract requirements, operational directives or needs, and historical archiving. When personal information is removed from our systems, it will be deleted or destroyed using appropriate security protocols so that it cannot be reconstructed or read.

### Choice/Opt-Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about the user.

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database in order to not receive future communications or to no longer receive our services:

  * You can send an email to [privacy@windriver.com](mailto:privacy@windriver.com).
  * You can send mail to the postal address at the bottom of this page.

### Access/Correct/Update

This site gives users the following options for accessing, changing, modifying and/or deleting information previously provided to us:

  * You can send an email to [webmaster@windriver.com](mailto:webmaster@windriver.com) or to [privacy@windriver.com](mailto:privacy@windriver.com).
  * You can send mail to the postal address at the bottom of this page.

For your protection, we will only implement requests with respect to personal information about you (not anyone else), and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable and in accordance with applicable law. We may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes, as required under applicable legal obligations, and/or to complete any transactions that you began prior to requesting such change or deletion (e.g., when you make a purchase or enter a promotion, you may not be able to change or delete the personal information provided until after the completion of such purchase or promotion). Some of your information may remain within our systems and other records, in compliance with applicable law.

At your request and where the law requires us to do so, we will confirm what personal information we hold about you. You may also have a legal right to obtain a copy of your personal information. You can make such a request by making a written request to the address indicated below. We may charge a processing fee for this service where permitted by law and we will require evidence of your identity before fulfilling your request.

### Changes to this Privacy Notice

We may change this Privacy Notice from time to time so it accurately reflects our practices, Wind River services and legal requirements. You should check back regularly to stay informed of our privacy practices. Any changes to this Privacy Notice will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Notice subject to this section.

If any change to our Privacy Notice materially affects the use of your personal information, we will use reasonable efforts to notify you in advance, such as by sending an email or posting a prominent notice of the changes on our website, and give you a reasonable period of time to object to any changes. In some cases, objecting to changes may affect the availability or functionality of the Wind River services available to you. 

We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Notice to stay informed about how we collect, use, and share personal information.

### Notice

We provide access to our Privacy Notice by:

  * Linking to it throughout our websites
  * Referencing it in our Terms of Use
  * Incorporating it into our contracts, agreements, and other documents as necessary or appropriate

### Contacting Wind River

If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about this Privacy Notice, the practices of Wind River, or your dealings with Wind River, you can contact:

Wind River Systems, Inc.  
ATTN: Privacy Office  
500 Wind River Way  
Alameda, CA 94501
